Hi guys.
So by now you can probably guess that in this process group we are bringing together all the monitoring
and controlling tasks from all the knowledge areas.
So basically it is in this process we are going to make sure that all the baselines are maintained and
not if we did our project management plan is followed if there are any deviations corrective action
is taken and wherever possible we can take preventive action to avoid any evasion of the standard operating
procedures or established plan.
You will also receive the chinch control so you need to make sure that those Change Request are reviewed
and approved or declined based upon the planned activities and the plan guidelines and monitoring and
controlling your daily activity.
In fact once a project is in the execution phase as a project manager you won't be involved with the
actual activity or activity core task and responsibility will be leading your team communicating with
all the stakeholders and monitoring and controlling the project.
You need to make sure that whatever standards were established are expected they should be followed
and nobody is doing anything which deviating from the standard processes.
For example let's say business analysis is going on.
The comments are pending but your programmers haven't started to charge.
WB has called for programming.
So in that case the timesheet when it comes to you for approval you need to reach out to those programmers
and confirm why they are doing that.
Because sometimes programmers won't have anything else to do and to just to charge some time and they
will use to assign the blue be a score.
Same thing can happen with other groups like coding is going on.
It's not yet available for testing but testers have started to charge time.
If they do that over a period of time actual numbers are going to be much higher than expected.
Let's say 50 us are assigned for their task.
Testers have already charged 20 hours before their work was delivered to them for testing.
Now they are going to take 50 or so or all charging would be 70 hours versus the assigned 50 hours.
And it will be reflected in the reports because these times use all these tools are used for tracking
and analytical purpose so at the end of the project over and over and those reports will be generated.
The sponsors are going to come after you.
That why you allowed such activity to happen.
So you need to make sure that nobody is charging extra.
These others are processes from all the knowledge IZEA So we have all discovered them.
We need to make sure that project manager is monitoring and controlling the project work DEP forming
the integrator change control validating school condoling scoops to do cost quality resources and monitoring
communication interest along with controlling procurements and stakeholder engagement monitoring.
So it's very important to perform all of these activities here.
If you have any doubt on a new subprocess you can always go back to those knowledge areas and the effort
of these individual routines.
But for all our monitoring is very important.
Next we are going to look at last.
We do of this section which is closing the project.
Thank you.